#### Contact

+39 389 8372661 (Mobile) alex.osster.web@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/alex-osster (LinkedIn) osster.github.io/ (Personal)

#### Top Skills

Software Development Project Management Laravel

# Aleksandr Komar

Full Stack Engineer

Greater Naples Metropolitan Area

### Summary

I was trained to be a programmer-economist, and my first experience was precisely in that field. It involved an accounting desktop product with a vast number of relations, reports, and complex SQL queries.

When I hit the ceiling, a hobby emerged in the form of website development, which smoothly turned into a 24/7 occupation. Since then, I've been in the web.

Over the past decade, I've worked on quite a large number of projects in various capacities and roles.

I enjoy challenges, so I've been focused on startups that help create new opportunities for people. Each challenge involves a number of related technologies, and it's very fulfilling when I'm able to use new stacks to grow and improve the product I'm working on. That's why my new hobby is exploring new opportunities.

More details over a cup of coffee.

## Experience

BitMobi Software Developer April 2021 - Present (2 years 10 months) London, England, United Kingdom

Private Unitary Enterprise "Applar"
Full Stack Engineer
March 2019 - November 2020 (1 year 9 months)
Minsk, Belarus
ezLoads TMS

All in one place

Integrated transportation management system helps you save time and money. Book loads, dispatch, invoice, pay drivers, and track loads from anywhere.

The heart of application is php framework Laravel. As frontend has been used Nuxt.js SPA based on Vue.js framework. UI based on bootstrap. Environment implemented as Docker containers.

The goal of application is simplify job for tracking company operators. App helps to calculate all route stops, fees and working hours for truck drivers. So operator need couple mouse clicks to build all route with all stops for multiple loads/reloads in different states. Application support only North American tracking.

A new web application was developed. The app was tested in real time in several companies, so the first commercial version of the app was stable. After two months of marketing we reached our first 100+ customers, which covers all development over the next 12 months.

LLC "Agency of Event Projects Alter Ego Group" Head of Development Department March 2018 - January 2019 (11 months) Minsk, Belarus

Hunting designers, developers, technical interviews & internal courses (PHP, Laravel, JS, Node.js, Nuxt.js, Vue.js, jQuery, CSS, SCSS, SASS, Webpack, Bootstrap).

Negotiations with clients, drawing up technical tasks, control of current tasks, launch of projects, presentations.

A department of the company was created. We completed around 10 projects before the economic crisis killed the business and consequently our main clients.

web creator studio Individual entrepreneur January 2014 - January 2018 (4 years 1 month)

Full stack website development mostly PHP CMS Joomla (couple times PHP framework Laravel & PHP framework Codelgniter), Mysql, bootstrap, CSS, SCSS, jQuery. SEO optimisation and basic SEO support.

Self-Employed Freelance Web Developer 2009 - 2014 (5 years)

Moscow, Russia

Full stack website development mostly PHP CMS Joomla, Mysql, bootstrap, CSS, SCSS, jQuery.

GIVC "Ministry of Agriculture and Food" Software Engineer October 2005 - April 2009 (3 years 7 months) Minsk, Belarus

Development, integration and implementation of accounting and reporting system in agriculture "NIVA SHP" based on "Gedimin" platform.

Desktop application on delpy 5 platform with integrated VBScript/ Firebird(Interbase) server/form editor/code editor/ql editor.

Specific documents used in agricultural organizations have been integrated into the platform. Taking into account these documents was supplemented the system to calculate the salaries of employees. Also the system of accounting of fodder, fertilizers and crops was implemented.

New national system has been developed.

### Education

**IIT BSUIR Minsk** 

Engineer-programmer-economist, Information systems and technologies (in economics) · (2005 - 2010)

Minsk State Higher Radio Engineering College electronics technician, Electronic computing facilities · (2001 - 2005)